Guide to the Ronald Reis photographs, 1954-2014 RL.01078
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Ronald Reis photographs
1954-2014
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Reis, Ronald, 1916?-2014
RL.01078
20.5 Linear Feet 26 boxes; approximately 4018 items
The images in this collection were taken by photographer Ron Reis from the 1950s to 1979 and from 2004 to 2014. The earlier body of work (1962-1974) contains 289 black-and-white photographs, accompanied by negatives and contact sheets. The later body of work (2004-2014) contains 3,719 black-and-white and color laser inkjet prints, with a majority of images dated 2012 to 2013. Reis focused his camera on street scenes primarily in New York and New England, but also in Colorado and the midwest, in Europe (Italy, England, Ireland, and Greece), and in the Middle East. His images capture anti-war demonstrations, feminist and gay pride parades, and ethnic festivals, while also documenting the more quotidian life of urban neighborhoods, street markets, and other public spaces such as Speakers' Corner in London's Hyde Park and New York City's Washington Square. The earlier black-and-white gelatin silver prints measure 11x14 inches, while the laser inkjet prints measure 11x17 inches. There are also manuscript and printed materials such as a curriculum vitae, some correspondence, exhibition publicity, articles, and photo essays. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Collection Overview
The images in this collection were taken by photographer Ron Reis from the 1950s to 1979 and from 2004 to 2014. The earlier body of work contains 289 black-and-white photographs, accompanied by negatives and contact sheets, and consists of documentary images taken by Reis during the 1960s and 1970s, primarily in Connecticut, London, and New York City, with a smaller number from major European cities. The later body of work contains 3,719 laser inkjet prints of black-and-white and color documentary images taken by Reis in the 2000s, with a majority of images dated 2012 to 2013. Most of these images are of New York City street scenes.
An avid amateur street photographer influenced by Cartier-Bresson, Helen Levitt, and Louis Stettner, Reis focused his camera on street scenes in the United States, Europe, and the Middle East during the 1960s, then in the 2000s. Favorite locations chosen by Reis include London's Hyde Park Speakers' Corner, Portobello flea market, and Trafalgar Square; New York's Bryant Park, Greenwich Village, and Washington Square; and market scenes in Connecticut and Jerusalem. Other images portray anti-Vietnam War protests in Bryant Park, gay pride and ethnic festivals and parades, amusement parks, and other street scenes.
The collection is arranged in three series: Photographs, Negatives, and Manuscript and Print Materials.
The Photographs Series is divided into two chronological subseries: 1954-1979 and 2004-2014. The first subseries contains 289 11x14-inch gelatin silver prints, accompanied by negatives and contact sheets. These black-and-white images were taken by Reis during the 1960s and 1970s, primarily in Connecticut, London, and New York City, with a smaller number from Athens, Barcelona, Como, Dublin, Florence, Jerusalem, London, Rome, and Venice. In general, each 8x10-inch contact sheet is followed by selected prints from the same roll. The prints and contacts are organized chronologically.
The second subseries contains 3,719 inkjet prints, both black-and-white and color, the vast majority measuring 11x17 inches. The prints, taken between 2004 and 2014, consist mostly of New York City street scenes as well as photographs from Reis's trips to Canada, Colorado, Connecticut, Vermont, Maine, Pennsylvania, Indiana, Illinois, Missouri, and North Carolina. These photographs are described at the folder level, with folders containing up to 80 prints.
The Manuscript and Print Materials include an early curriculum vita, some correspondence, exhibition fliers, negative sleeves, articles, and photo essays.
The Negatives Series is arranged by year and month, and titles were taken from original notes on the negative envelopes. They overlap with the prints in the collection to some degree, but there are also negatives present for images that are not currently in the collection.
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Biographical Note
Ron (Ronald E.) Reis began taking photographs as a child with an Argus A2. He shot sports photography in junior high school with an Argus C-3 and an Ansco Reflex. He continued photographing sports, acquiring cameras, and developing his darkroom skills throughout high school. When he moved to Philadelphia in 1953 to attend the University of Pennsylvania, Reis turned his 35mm Leica from the sports fields to the streets.
Influenced by the work of Helen Levitt, Louis Stettner, and Cartier-Bresson, Reis became a passionate street photographer, honing his ability to compose and capture photographs on the fly. This decisive quality is reflected in his contacts sheets filled with single exposures. Reis primarily photographed in New York, Connecticut and Europe during the 1960s. The collection captures the look and feel of the 1960s, especially in the cities of New York City and London.
Reis's photographic work has been exhibited at the Worcester Art Museum, Dartmouth College, the A.T. Gallery in New Haven Connecticut, the New Britain Museum of American Art, the E. Leitz Gallery in New York, and the Image Gallery in New York. In addition, several of his prints were exhibited, as the only amateur photographer, in a Christmas show at the Witkin Gallery in New York City as well as in a one-man show at Parents Magazine Gallery in New York City. His work has been published in Camera 35, Leica Magazine, Popular Photography, and U.S. Camera. Permanent collections of his images reside at Duke University's Rubenstein Library, in the Worcester Art Museum (Worcester, Massachusetts), the Museum of American Art in New Britain, Connecticut, and the British Institute of Contemporary Arts in London.
Ronald Reis died in New York City in April 2014.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, original negatives are open to use only with permission of Curator of the Archive of Documentary Arts.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Ronald Reis photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2010, 2014, and 2015.
Documentary Photography -- Europe; Documentary Photography -- United States; Ethnic festivals -- United States; Gay pride parades -- United States; Photographers -- United States; Protest movements -- United States; Street photography -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Street photography -- New York (State) -- New York; Street photography -- United States; Athens (Greece) -- Photographs; Barcelona (Spain) -- Photographs; Connecticut -- Photographs; Dublin (Ireland) -- Photographs; England -- Pictorial works; Florence (Italy) -- Photographs; Italy -- Photographs; Jerusalem -- Photographs; London (England) -- Photographs; New York (N.Y.) -- Photographs; Rome (Italy) -- Photographs; Black-and-white photographs; Color photographs; Contact sheets; Gelatin silver prints; Inkjet prints; Negatives (photographs); Reis, Ronald, 1916?-2014; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
- Photographs, 1962-2014 and undated
  Scope and Contents
  These exhibit-quality photographs are in black-and-white as well as in color. The earliest are darkroom prints, and are accompanied by contact sheets, while later work (after 2004) is most often in digital color and black-and-white inkjet format. They are printed in a range of sizes, chiefly 11x14 and 11x17 inches, but there are some also as small as 6 3/8 x 9 1/2 inches. The images are arranged by topical or geographical photo shoots, in chronological order, with original titles as assigned by Reis.
  - Photographs and contact sheets, 1962-1979, 6 boxes
    Scope and Contents note
    Folders house 289 prints and contact sheets. Each contact sheet has an identifier assigned by Reis and derived from the roll number, which notes the month and year plus a letter code (e.g., 6/1962G or 07-1962F). Each print also is identified by the roll id followed by a numeral (6/1962G-01). Print sizes vary from 6 3/8 x 9.5 inches up to 11 x 14 inches. All contact sheets are 8x10 inches. Identification number ranges on each folder represent the prints and contact sheets housed within. Arranged in order by id number.
    - West Haven, CT: Savin Rock amusement park [contact sheet], 1962 June (Box 1, Print rrcs 06-1962G)
    - New York City: Guggenheim Museum [contact sheet], 1962 July (Box 1, Print rrcs 07-1962F)
    - New York City: street scene, 1962-07 (Box 1, Print rrpp 07-1962F-9)
    - New York City: Guggenheim Museum, 1962 July (Box 1, Print rrph 07-1962F-18)
    - New Haven, CT: street scene [contact sheet], 1962 Aug. (Box 1, Print rrcs 08-1962G)
    - New Haven, CT: children on steps, 1962 Aug. (Box 1, Print rrph 08-1962G-8)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1962 Aug. (Box 1, Print rrcs 08-1962J)
    - West Haven, CT: Savin Rock amusement park, 1962 Aug. (Box 1, Print rrph 08-1962J-2)
    - New York City: street scene, 1962 Aug. (Box 1, Print rrph 08-1962J-7)
    - New York City: New York Public Library on 42nd Street [contact sheet], 1962 Aug. (Box 1, Print rrcs 08-1962L)
    - New York City: New York Public Library on 42nd Street, 1962 Aug. (Box 1, Print rrph 08-1962L-2)
    - New York City: street scene, 1962 Aug. (Box 1, Print rrph 08-1962L-9)
    - New York City: Bryant Park, 1962 Aug. (Box 1, Print rrph 08-1962L-12)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park [contact sheet], 1962 Sept. (Box 1, Print rrcs 09-1962C)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park, 1962 Sept. (Box 1, Print rrph 09-1962C-12)
    - New Haven, CT: street scene [contact sheet], 1962 Sept. (Box 1, Print rrcs 09-1962D)
    - New Haven, CT: street scene, 1962 Sept. (Box 1, Print rrph 09-1962D-9)
    - Philadelphia: shoe shine boys, University of Pennsylvania, 1962 Oct. (Box 1, Print rrpp 10-1962C-00)
    - West Haven, CT: Savin Rock amusement park [contact sheet], 1962 Nov. (Box 1, Print rrcs 11-1962R)
    - New York City: newsstand, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963A-x1)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner [contact sheet], 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrcs 03-1963E)
    - London: street scene, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963E-12)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963E-19)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963E-34)
    - London: Portobello Road flea market [contact sheet], 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrcs 03-1963F)
    - London: Portobello Road flea market, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963F-05)
    - London: Portobello Road flea market, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963F-06)
    - London: Portobello Road flea market, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963F-11)
    - London: Portobello Road flea market, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963F-16)
    - London: Portobello Road flea market, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963F-24)
    - London: Portobello Road flea market, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963F-27)
    - London: street scene, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963F-36)
    - London: Portobello Road flea market, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963F-x)
    - London: street scene [contact sheet], 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrcs 03-1963G)
    - London: street scene, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963G-05)
    - London: Buckingham Palace tourist, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963G-09)
    - London: Buckingham Palace police, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963G-14)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner [contact sheet], 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrcs 03-1963H)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963H-01)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963H-03)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963H-12)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963H-22)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963H-24)
    - London: street scene [contact sheet], 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrcs 03-1963J)
    - London: Trafalgar Square, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963J-07)
    - London: Trafalgar Square [contact sheet], 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrcs 03-1963K)
    - London: Trafalgar Square, 1963 Mar. (Box 1, Print rrph 03-1963K-31)
    - New York City: parade, 1963 June (Box 1, Print rrph 06-1963F-x1)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park [contact sheet], 1963 June (Box 1, Print rrcs 06-1963J)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park, 1963 June (Box 1, Print rrph 06-1963J-15)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park, 1963 June (Box 1, Print rrph 06-1963J-17)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park [contact sheet], 1963 June (Box 1, Print rrcs 06-1963L)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park, 1963 June (Box 1, Print rrph 06-1963L-03)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park, 1963 June (Box 1, Print rrph 06-1963L-11)
    - New York City: Greenwich Village, 1963 June (Box 1, Print rrph 06-1963L-33)
    - St. Louis, MO: park [contact sheet], 1963 June (Box 1, Print rrcs 06-1963N)
    - St. Louis, MO: park, 1963 June (Box 1, Print rrph 06-1963N-26A)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park [contact sheet], 1963 July (Box 1, Print rrcs 07-1963B)
    - New York City: street scene, 1963 July (Box 1, Print rrph 07-1963B-00)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park, 1963 July (Box 1, Print rrph 07-1963B-18)
    - New York City: Greenwich Village [contact sheet], 1963 Aug. (Box 1, Print rrcs 08-1963H)
    - New York City: Greenwich Village, street fair, 1963 Aug. (Box 1, Print rrph 08-1963H-11)
    - New York City: woman modeling clothes [contact sheet], 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrcs 10-1963A)
    - New York City: New York Public Library on 42nd Street, 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrph 10-1963A-02)
    - Danbury, CT: Danbury State Fair [contact sheet], 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrcs 10-1963B)
    - Danbury, CT: Danbury State Fair, 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrph 10-1963B-21)
    - Danbury, CT: Danbury State Fair [contact sheet], 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrcs 10-1963C)
    - Danbury, CT: Danbury State Fair, 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrph 10-1963C-01)
    - Danbury, CT: Danbury State Fair, 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrph 10-1963C-03)
    - Danbury, CT: Danbury State Fair, 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrph 10-1963C-10)
    - West Haven, CT: Savin Rock amusement park [contact sheet], 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrcs 10-1963H)
    - West Haven, CT: Savin Rock amusement park, 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrph 10-1963H-32)
    - West Haven, CT: Savin Rock amusement park, 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrph 10-1963H-39)
    - West Haven, CT: Savin Rock amusement park [contact sheet], 1963 Oct. (Box 2, Print rrcs 10-1963J)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1963 Nov. (Box 2, Print rrcs 11-1963B)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park, 1963 Nov. (Box 2, Print rrph 11-1963B-36)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park, 1963 Nov. (Box 2, Print rrph 11-1963B-68)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1963 Dec. (Box 2, Print rrcs 12-1963D)
    - New York City: street scene, 1963 Dec. (Box 2, Print rrph 12-1963D-8a)
    - New York City: newsstand, 1963 Dec. (Box 2, Print rrph 12-1963D-13)
    - Hamden, CT: church creche [contact sheet], 1963 Dec. (Box 2, Print rrcs 12-1963H)
    - Hamden, CT: church creche, 1963 Dec. (Box 2, Print rrph 12-1963H-07)
    - Italy: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrcs 04-1964A)
    - Rome: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964A-17)
    - Naples, Italy: Roma women on the street, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964A-23)
    - Italy: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964A-28)
    - Rome: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrcs 04-1964B)
    - Rome: Via Veneto, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964B-04)
    - Rome: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964B-23a)
    - Rome: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964B-28)
    - Rome: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964B-29)
    - Rome: priest with school boys, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964B-34)
    - Florence, Italy: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrcs 04-1964C)
    - Florence, Italy: street tour guide, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964C-01)
    - Florence, Italy: fishing on the Arno River, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964C-23)
    - Florence, Italy: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964C-27)
    - Florence, Italy: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964C-31)
    - Como, Italy: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrcs 04-1964D)
    - Como, Italy: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964D-21)
    - Como, Italy: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964D-23)
    - Florence, Italy: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrcs 04/1964E)
    - Florence, Italy: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964E-03)
    - Florence, Italy: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964E-08)
    - Florence, Italy: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964E-26)
    - Florence, Italy: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964E-28)
    - Italy: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrcs 04-1964F)
    - Florence, Italy: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964F-10)
    - Venice: St. Mark's Square, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964F-22)
    - Venice: St. Mark's Square, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964F-24)
    - Italy and England: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrcs 04-1964G)
    - Venice: canal scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964G-02)
    - Venice: musicians in a café, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964G-05)
    - Venice: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964G-19)
    - Venice: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964G-21)
    - London: school boys, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964G-26a)
    - London: school boy, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964G-27)
    - Venice: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964G-34)
    - Italy and England: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrcs 04-1964H)
    - Italy: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964H-11)
    - London: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964H-24)
    - London: Portobello Road flea market, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964H-26)
    - London: Portobello Road flea market, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964H-28)
    - London: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 2, Print rrph 04-1964H-33)
    - London: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrcs 04-1964J)
    - London: Trafalgar Square, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964J-04)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964J-18a)
    - London: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrcs 04-1964K)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964K-05)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964K-14)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964K-16)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964K-18)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964K-25)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964K-30)
    - London: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrcs 04-1964L)
    - Dublin, Ireland: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964L-10)
    - London: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964L-19)
    - London: Rockers in Trafalgar Square, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964L-30)
    - Ireland and England: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrcs 04-1964M)
    - London: Trafalgar Square, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964M-05)
    - London: street scene, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964M-21a)
    - Dublin, Ireland: stone mason, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964M-25)
    - London: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrcs 04-1964N)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964N-01)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964N-02)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964N-06)
    - London: Hyde Park Speaker's Corner, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964N-07)
    - London: Green Park, 1964 Apr. (Box 3, Print rrph 04-1964N-11)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 June (Box 3, Print rrcs 06-1964A)
    - New York City: Little Italy, 1964 June (Box 3, Print rrph 06-1964A-0a)
    - New York City: Greenwich Village, 1964 June (Box 3, Print rrph 06-1964A-1a)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 June (Box 3, Print rrcs 06-1964B)
    - New York City: Little Italy, 1964 June (Box 3, Print rrph 06-1964B-23)
    - New York City: Little Italy, 1964 June (Box 3, Print rrph 06-1964B-27)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 June (Box 3, Print rrcs 06-1964C)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park, 1964 June (Box 3, Print rrph 06-1964C-9a)
    - New York City: Hudson River, "City of Keansburg" sightseeing boat, 1964 June (Box 3, Print rrph 06-1964C-27a)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 June (Box 3, Print rrcs 06-1964D)
    - New York City: Madison Square Park, 1964 June (Box 3, Print rrph 06-1964D-09)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 July (Box 3, Print rrcs 07-1964D)
    - New York City: Lower East Side, 1964 July (Box 3, Print rrph 07-1964D-16a)
    - New York City: Lower East Side, 1964 July (Box 3, Print rrph 07-1964D-23a)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Aug. (Box 3, Print rrcs 08-1964J)
    - New York City: Lower East Side, 1964 Aug. (Box 3, Print rrph 08-1964J-3a)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Sept. (Box 3, Print rrcs 09-1964D)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park, 1964 Sept. (Box 3, Print rrph 09-1964D-20)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Sept. (Box 3, Print rrcs 09-1964E)
    - New York City: Greenwich Village, 1964 Sept. (Box 3, Print rrph 09-1964E-14a)
    - Meriden, CT: motorcycle race [contact sheet], 1964 Oct. (Box 3, Print rrcs 10-1964A)
    - Meriden, CT: motorcycle race, 1964 Oct. (Box 3, Print rrph 10-1964A-23a)
    - Meriden, CT: motorcycle race [contact sheet], 1964 Oct. (Box 4, Print rrcs 10-1964B)
    - Meriden, CT: motorcycle race, 1964 Oct. (Box 4, Print rrph 10-1964B-1a)
    - Meriden, CT: motorcycle race, 1964 Oct. (Box 4, Print rrph 10-1964B-7a)
    - Meriden, CT: motorcycle race, 1964 Oct. (Box 4, Print rrph 10-1964B-9a)
    - New York City: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Oct. (Box 4, Print rrcs 10-1964C)
    - New York City: Greenwich Village, 1964 Oct. (Box 4, Print rrph 10-1964C-7)
    - New York City and England: street scene [contact sheet], 1964 Oct. (Box 4, Print rrcs 10-1964E)
    - New York City: Lower East Side, 1964 Oct. (Box 4, Print rrph 10-1964E-7)
    - New York City: Lower East Side, 1964 Oct. (Box 4, Print rrph 10-1964E-8)
    - New York City: Washington Square Park, 1964 Oct. (Box 4, Print rrph 10-1964E-15a)